# **Helen Ingham**



1 Leeds, West Yorkshire









A solution-focused and technically competent Front-End Developer, highly experienced in JavaScript, React.js, React-Router, React Native, Node.js, Express.js, RESTful APIs, SQL, UI/UX, GraphQL, and other technologies, implementing the best strategies that improve workflows, services, and teams. Having architected and developed technical solutions, I excel at driving all phases of projects by transforming simple requirements into quantifiable growth and revenue, building and configuring secure products, visualizing, and delivering expected results. Committed professional, highly organized, capable to work under pressure with progressive teams to implement solutions that perform.

#### **Skills**

- JavaScript, ¡Query, React.is, React-Router, React Lifecycle Methods, React Styled Components, React Native, Node.js, Express.js, Knex.js, Leaflet, Firebase, Axios
- HTML5, CSS3, Figma, UI/UX, responsive techniques
- Data Structure, Algorithms, Software Design, SDLC, MVC
- Database administration, SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, GraphQL
- RESTful APIs, CRUD operations, Crawling, TDD (Test-Driven Development), Debugging, OOP, HTTP Servers, Heroku
- Git, GitHub, Git workflows
- Agile Methodology, SCRUM

# **Projects**

## Travel Buddy / GitHub Frontend, GitHub Backend, Video Presentation

A React-based web application where users can explore the hidden gems of travel submitted by fellow travelers to create a truly authentic travel experience based on local tips and other valuable insights.

TECH STACK: React.js, Leaflet, Firebase, Styled Components, Axios, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, Knex.

#### **Professional Career**

JULY 2016 - DECEMBER 2019

### Assistant Headteacher / Boroughbridge High School, North Yorkshire

- Acted as a visible member of the SLT, contributing to the strategic development of the school by participating in arrangements for further training and professional learning
- Attended at Senior Leadership Team meetings, Governors' meetings, and other school events, facilitating the relationships between our institution and pupils, parents, and other staff members
- Actively engaged in the performance management review process, complying with financial, safety, data protection, and child protection requirements to ensure a sustainable future for the following generations
- Developed transition programs and other strategies that automated existing workflows, closely monitoring the behavior and attendance across the school which allowed us to implement action in response that fixed potential problems and breaches
- Monitored and reviewed the school's PDBW processes, proposing and implementing ideas that were quickly adopted and put into practice
- Performed teaching and other usual operations that allowed me to have a positive impact on the student's careers and future plans

SEPTEMBER 2012 - AUGUST 2016

#### Assistant Principal: Behaviour and Safety / Oasis Academy Lister Park, Bradford, West Yorkshire

- Promoted a quality learning environment focused on punctuality, safety, and friendship, following well-established regulations
- In charge of safeguarding and child protection, making sure that vulnerable groups were following the correct path to success
- Performed teaching 0.4 timetable English GCSE, developing entertaining projects that actively involved even the most-timid students
- Actively involved in promoting a good discipline while managing exclusions and reintegration programs that generated expected results

SEPTEMBER 2011 - AUGUST 2012

### Fixed Term Assistant Headteacher / Addington High School, Croydon, Outer London

- Raised Attainment Lead, tracked and targeted setting for GCSE results including leading the whole school work
- Managed various departments, acting as a Deputy Design Professional for Safeguarding, ensuring that established rules and policies were followed and respected
- Performed teaching 0.4 timetable English GCSE, using modern methods that attracted the student's interest and satisfaction

SEPTEMBER 2006 - AUGUST 2011

## Head of Year / Addington High School, Croydon, Outer London

- Led a group of 180 students from year 8 until year 11, taking two-year groups through year 11, working closely with their parents and other key stakeholders to generate expected results
- Responsible for the pastoral and academic leadership of the students and staff, building a whole school ethos with a team of Heads of Year

- Designed and wrote a PHSE Programme to be delivered during tutorials that facilitated integrations for existing processes
- Managed the transition to 6<sup>th</sup> form/college for year 11, as well as teaching 0.6 timetable English for years 7 11, including other subjects

SEPTEMBER 2004 - AUGUST 2006

## English Teacher / Addington High School, Croydon, Outer London

- Developed instructional strategies, materials, and methodologies for the Inclusion of English learners
- Built short and long-range lesson plans that encouraged a positive learning environment and an excellent student-teacher interaction
- Prepared students for high-level English exams through a continuous review, encouragement, and support
- Successfully communicated with other teachers to improve the teaching curriculum in a highly friendly, fast, and secure environment

#### **Education**

JUNE 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020

**Graduated in Software Development / Northcoders Bootcamp** 

SEPTEMBER 2014 - JULY 2016

National Qualification for Headship / Carnegie Teaching Schools' Alliance with Leeds Beckett University – Licensed by the National College for Teaching and Leadership

**JULY 2015** 

Qualified Teacher Status / Teach First through Canterbury Christ Church University

JUNE 2011 – NOVEMBER 2011

Leadership Pathways / NCFE, through the Institute of Education (London)

SEPTEMBER 2001 - JUNE 2004

BA (Hons) in History of Art with English Literature / University of Birmingham